A Guide to the John S. and James L. Knight Foundation records, Awards and Artifacts, RG 9 FA1803
Rockefeller Archive Center
John S. and James L. Knight Foundation records, Awards and Artifacts, RG 9
1990-2014
Rockefeller Archive Center
John S. and James L. Knight Foundation
FA1803
2.25 Cubic Feet 6 containers: 1 half legal box; 2 letter boxes, 3 card file boxes
3 Gigabytes
Conditions Governing Access
Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Arrangement
As received.
Scope and Contents
Record Group 9 contains awards and artifacts from various Knight Foundation programs. Most of the material in this collection is comprised of physical awards and objects, only a small amount of material is paper records.
- Artifacts, 2005-2014; 1; 0.62 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box and 1 half-legal box
  - Dies of Knight Foundation, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General
    Knight File Number - 2418
    Scope and Contents
    Three dies - one of Knight Foundation and two of "KF" (different sizes) used for printing.
  - Plaque: Antique Wood Type, 2010 September 11 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Knight File Number - 5535
    Metal plaque re: antique wood type, metal type and engravings was presented to KF by Lloyd Schermer, the artist who created the large piece, Wisdom's Puzzle I, 2004, which is in the KF board room. The plaque explains the printing process and type which have been used to create the art piece.
  - Black Male Engagement (BME) Program, 2011 October 17 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Knight File Number - 4966
    Black Male Engagement (BME) Challenge, an initiative co-sponsored by Open Society Foundation's Campaign for Black Male Achievement and KF, held a BME Challenge Celebration in Detroit. Artifacts are: a program.
  - Martin Luther King, Jr. Memorial, 2011 August 28 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Knight File Number - 4976
    Gold commemorative medallion issued on the opening of the MLK memorial in Washington, DC; invitation to the dedication; and Memorial booklet. KF was a sponsor of the memorial.
  - Knight News Challenge pins, 2012-2014 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Knight File Number - 5483
    Four pins with a cardboard holder commemorating the Knight News Challenge 2012. The pins include images of the KF logo, a "retro" cell phone, a dog, and abstract image. Also included are 8 additional pins, which were distributed in 2013 and 2014 and feature cartoon-type figures.
  - Media Learning Seminar: Information Needs of Communities in a Democracy, 2009 February 16-17 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Knight File Number - 4451
    Materials presented to participants attending the seminar, which took place in Coral Gables, FL. The seminar was jointly sponsored by the Knight Foundation and the Council on Foundations. Presentation items consisted of a notebook and pen and a copy of featured speaker Gwen Ifil's book, "The Break-through: politics and race in the age of Obama". (The book has been put in the KF library collection.)
  - Broadcast in a Box: A Toolkit for Teaching High School Electronic Journalism, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Knight File Number - 5069
    Kit contains: Great Ideas for your Classroom - Booklet and DVD; The First Amendment - Keep It Strong - CD-ROM; RTNDA's Code of Ethics and Professional Conduct - wallet sized; Plugged In: Using the Internet for High School (and Professional) Journalism - booklet; Reaching Generation Next: A News Media Guide to Creating Successful High School Partnerships - Book. The toolkit was supported by the Knight Foundation.
  - Broadcast in a Box: High School Electronic Journalism Project (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
  - Broadcast in a Box: The First Amendment - Keep It Strong! - TV Spots (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Broadcast in a Box: The First Amendment - Keep It Strong! - Curriculum and Teaching Guide for 45 Words of Freedom (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Civics and Citizenship Toolkit, 2007 (Box 5)
    Knight File Number - 4740
    Kit contains resource literature, flash cards, and DVD, all aimed at easing the transition of permanent residents into American culture and into citizenship.
- Awards, 1990-2013; 2; 2.01 Cubic Feet 3 letter document boxes and 2 card file boxes
  - Communications Department Awards and Certificates, 1990 November 6-2004 March 17 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Knight File Number - 2412
    Includes submissions, citations and certificates re: The Wilmer Shields Rich Awards for Excellence in Communications and the ACE Awards competition sponsored by the Akron chapter of Women in Communications, Inc.
  - Knight News Challenge Award 2007, 2007 May 23 (Box 3)
    Knight File Number - 4346
    Glass, desktop, award for winners of the Knight News Challenge.
  - Knight News Challenge Award, 2008 (Box 2)
    Knight File Number - 4347
    Glass award with metal stand given to Knight News Challenge winners.
  - Knight Arts Partnership Award, 2008 (Box 3)
    Knight File Number - 4420
    Glass award given to Knight Arts Partnership winners.
  - Knight Named Outstanding National Foundation of the Year, 2009 October 26 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    File Plan
    Knight File Number - 4579
    The award was presented by the Association of Fundraising Professionals. This is a memo explaining the award, which was presented in 2010.
  - Knight Arts Award, 2009 December (Box 6)
    Knight File Number - 4650
    Glass award given to Knight Arts winners.
  - Knight News Challenge Award, 2010-2011 (Box 3)
    Knight File Number - 4749
    Glass award given to Knight News Challenge winners.
  - Knight Arts Winner Awards 2010, 2011, 2012, 2013, 2010-2013 (Box 3)
    Knight File Number - 4813
    Glass awards given to Knight Arts Challenge winners in the Miami area (2010, 2011, 2012, 2013) and Philadelphia (2011, 2012). One 2013 Award is the People's Choice award.
  - Black Male Engagement Leadership Award, 2012 (Box 4)
    Knight File Number - 4987
    Glass award given to Black Male Engagement (BME) Leadership Award winners.